ORIGINAL STORY BY NATSU HYUUGA
（原作：日向夏）
THIS STORY IS A FICION, AND ALL NAMES OF FIGURES ND ORGANIZATIONS ARE FICTITIOUS.
（本作所有人物、组织名均为虚构 与任何特定事件或现象无关）
Hey!
喂
It's poison!
这有毒
You bastard! Who gave you the order?!
你这个混蛋 是谁命令你这么做？
Wait.
等一下
First, we must treat the soldiers.
首先 我们得先医治这些士兵
-Poison? -The meal was prepared in the village.
-中毒？ -饭菜是在村庄准备的
We've captured the village chief
村长由于支持异族
for siding with the foreigners. We're awaiting your orders.
已经关押起来了 请您发落
Understood. Give me some time.
明白了 给我一点时间
Yes, sir.
是
Also…
另外…
I hear that you hired
我听说
a new lady-in-waiting for Concubine Gyokuyou's palace.
您给玉叶妃新请了一位贴身下人
Yes.
对
Concubine Gyokuyou has four attendants.
玉叶妃只有四位贴身下人
Another high-ranking concubine,
另一位上级妃
Concubine Lihua, has more than ten. It's far too few.
梨花妃却有超过十位的侍女 四位实在太少了
She has to maintain her honor as a high-ranking concubine.
得维持住她身为上级妃的脸面
Yes.
对
However, although Concubine Gyokuyou is a cheerful and calm woman,
但是 尽管玉叶妃 是一位开朗冷静的女性
she is also intelligent and cautious.
她也很聪明谨慎
I wouldn't hire just anyone as her attendant.
我不能随便找个人当她的贴身下人
Being the Emperor's favorite means
身为皇上的宠妃
she has to remain suspicious all the time.
代表她得时时刻刻保持警惕之心
Her life is always at risk.
她的性命无时无刻都有危险
So, who is this new attendant?
这位新的贴身下人是什么来头？
Gaoshun, I found the perfect chess piece.
高顺 我找到了一颗完美的棋子
It's that freckled maidservant.
是那位雀斑婢女
She's knowledgeable about medicine. We can use that.
她很懂医术 我们可以好好利用这一点
I see.
了解
But what if she uses that knowledge against us?
但要是她用医术反制我们呢？
We just have to make sure that doesn't happen.
我们只要确保不会发生那种事
It's easy.
那很简单
Just to be safe, I can use seduction.
为了安全起见 我可以诱惑她
I'm so jealous you get to attend to a high-ranking concubine!
你真好 可以服侍上级妃
I'm not happy about this.
心情好沉重
Huh?
什么？
Apothecary.
药师
Are you prepared for your move?
你准备好搬走了吗？
Yes. I'm heading to the Jade Pavilion soon.
对 我很快就会前往翡翠宫
Did you need anything?
你有什么事吗？
No, I don't need anything.
不 没事
What?
什么？
Then why is he here? Does he have nothing better to do?
他来这儿做什么？ 他没别的事好做吗？
Serve Concubine Gyokuyou diligently.
好好服侍玉叶妃
Excuse me.
恕我告辞
Good luck, Maomao!
猫猫 加油哦
So gross…
好恶心…
You're Maomao?
你就是猫猫？
Yes, ma'am.
是的
I'm the head lady-in-waiting for Lady Gyokuyou, Hongniang.
我是玉叶娘娘的侍女长红娘
I'll show you around the Jade Pavilion. Come with me.
我先带你熟悉翡翠宫 跟我来
Yes.
好
Welcome to the Jade Pavilion.
欢迎来到翡翠宫
We were waiting for you, Maomao.
我们都在等你 猫猫
Looks like Xiaoling welcomes you too.
看来小铃也很欢迎你
I look forward to having you around.
今天开始就麻烦你了
Yes, ma'am.
请多指教 娘娘
Here is the reception room.
这是前厅
This is where we welcome the guests.
我们会在这儿招待客人
So big…
好大哦
Here is the kitchen. We can make simple meals here.
这儿是膳房 可以在这儿准备简单的饭菜
Here's the living room.
这是正厅
Let me introduce everyone.
我来介绍你给大家认识
All the Jade Pavilion attendants.
翡翠宫所有的侍女
Gather around, everyone!
大家 来集合了
Yes, ma'am!
好的
Nice to meet you, I'm Yinghua.
很高兴认识你 我是樱花
Ask me anything, all right?
不懂的都可以问我
Hello, I'm Guiyuan. Nice to meet you.
你好 我是贵园 很高兴认识你
I'm Ailan.
我是爱蓝
It's very nice to meet you.
请多指教
I'm Maomao. Thank you for having me.
我是猫猫 也请各位多指教
We don't hire maidservants at the Jade Pavilion.
翡翠宫不会请婢女
So we split the tasks and do them ourselves.
我们会分工合作完成所有的杂务
It's the least we can do for Lady Gyokuyou
这是我们最起码能为玉叶娘娘做的事
so that she can be comfortable.
让她舒舒服服的
-Then I will also… -Oh!
-那我也… -对了
You relax in your room.
你可以去你的房间休息
Just be comfortable.
自在一点
Since you'll be doing the special task.
因为你会负责特别的工作
"Special task"?
“特别的工作”？
-Maomao, I'll show you to your room. -All right.
-猫猫 我带你去你的房间 -噢 好
Did you see her left arm?
你们看到她的左手臂了吗？
She tried her best to hide it with bandages, but it's scarred, right?
她用绷带隐藏起来了 但那是伤疤 对吧？
She was probably abused by her parents back at home,
可能是在家里被父母虐待了
and was sold off to the rear palace.
然后被卖到后宫
And to top it all off, she'll be doing such hard tasks…
除此之外 她还得负责那么辛苦的工作…
Oh, that poor girl!
真是可怜的孩子
-Just stay put until you're called. -Um…
-被传之前 你就好好待着吧 -那个…
Seems like I got promoted way up the ranks.
看来我被晋升到很高的位阶
The Jade Pavilion had a small team of staff.
翡翠宫的侍女人数很少
I knew they wouldn't be welcoming to newcomers.
我知道她们不会欢迎新来的人
But those eyes…
但她们的眼神…
Pity?
可怜我？
Why?
为什么？
Poison tester.
试毒人
That's your job, Apothecary.
药师 那就是你的工作
Poison…
毒…
Poison tester?
试毒人？
No, stay calm.
不行 冷静
The meals prepared for the concubines
准备给娘娘的膳食
are handled by several people before being carried in here.
在送达这儿之前 经过了好几个人的手
There's a chance of the meal being poisoned during this process.
在这段过程当中 有机会遭人下毒
When Concubine Gyokuyou became pregnant, her meal was
玉叶妃怀孕之后 她的膳食
poisoned twice.
被下了两次毒
The poison tester back then, an attendant, got nerve damaged and
那时负责试毒的侍女 她的神经因此受损严重
her arms and legs are still paralyzed.
她的手臂和双腿仍处于瘫痪状态
I see. That's why the attendants pity me…
原来如此 所以那群侍女才会可怜我
All right, then.
那么
If you will.
麻烦你了
This bowl…
这个碗…
No abnormality in color.
颜色没什么异常
No strange odors.
没有奇怪的气味
No numbness, either.
也不会麻麻的
This doesn't seem to be poisoned.
这似乎没有被下毒的迹象
Back at home in the pleasure district,
在花街的家里
I tested various poisons on my arms, calling them "experiments."
我用手臂试过各式各样的毒 我把那称做“实验”
This mad scientist…
这个疯狂的科学家…
I slowly got my body adjusted to poison,
我的身体渐渐适应了毒性
so most types of poison don't work on me.
所以大部分的毒素 在我身上起不了作用
Honestly, I'm not suited for the role of a poison tester.
老实说 我不太适合试毒人这份工作
But in a way, I was very lucky to get this position.
但某种程度而言 能得到这份职务 真算我走运
She's laughing…
她在笑…
I think you should serve the meals
我认为应该
in silver bowls, since it reacts to poison.
用银器来盛装食物 因为它对毒素会起反应
Sir Jinshi was right.
壬氏大人的判断没错
We used ceramic bowls on purpose. He wanted to test you.
我们是故意用陶碗的 他想要测试你
This was that man's plot all along?
原来都是那个人的阴谋？
Your skills can truly become poison and medicine.
没想到你既会制药 又了解毒
I was an apothecary by profession.
药师是我的专业
If we knew you could write,
要是让我们知道你识字的话
you could've gotten a higher salary.
明明能给你更高的薪俸
I was kidnapped and brought here.
我是被绑匪掳来这儿的
It infuriates me to think that the kidnappers are still being sent
而绑匪仍然可以获得我一部分的薪俸
a part of my salary.
一想到就让我很火大
You're saying you don't want to give them drinking money
你的意思是说 你宁愿降低自己的薪俸
so badly that you would cut down your own salary.
也不愿意给他们付酒钱 是吧？
Oh, no! This is very expensive.
糟糕了 这很值钱
An attendant's salary can't possibly pay for this.
侍女的薪俸根本买不起这种东西
You can't even send an allowance back home.
这样你也没法寄钱回家了
I should be asking you for money.
我该向你要钱才对
Oh, no! I'm sorry, ma'am.
唉 我很抱歉
Please take away money from my allowance.
请从我的零用金当中扣掉吧
If it's not enough, take away my savings.
如果不够的话 也把我的存款拿走吧
All right. I'll handle the paperwork.
好的 我来处理文书
Also…
还有…
An added salary for poison testers. It's danger money.
试毒人的额外薪俸 算是危险津贴吧
About the same pay as my current salary…
跟我目前的薪俸一样多
Because there's no money going to the kidnappers,
因为不用被绑匪抽佣
it's actually a raise.
这等于是加薪了
Thank you, ma'am.
谢谢你
She's good at using her carrots.
她很懂得耍手段
It's fine!
没关系啦
Just rest!
你好好休息就好
We already had enough people anyways.
总之 我们的人手很充足了
I'm so bored!
我好无聊
I'm only called upon as a poison tester
需要试毒的时候 她们才会传我
for the two meals and teatime at noon.
只有一天两餐 外加中午的午茶
I finally have my own room.
我终于有了自己的房间
If I had some poisonous snakes, I could do experiments…
如果我有一些毒蛇的话 我就能够做实验了
-Maomao? -Oink?
-猫猫？ -哼唧？
Did you call for me, Lady Gyokuyou?
玉叶娘娘 您叫我吗？
He called for you.
是他叫你来的
Why won't it work on her?
为什么在她身上没有用？
What business do you have today?
您今天有何贵事？
I received this from a soldier.
这是一名士兵送来给我的
Can you taste test it?
你可以试吃看看吗？
Bao buns?
包子？
It contains an aphrodisiac.
里面有春药
You know without eating it?
你不用吃就知道了？
It won't have any impact on your health.
对你的健康不会有任何影响
You're free to enjoy these.
你可以尽情享用
Considering who gave them to me, I can't just eat these…
考虑到是谁送过来的 我不能就这样吃下去…
You may get a visit from that person tonight.
那个人今晚可能会去探视你
Disappointing. She can tell just by the smell?
什么嘛 她用闻的就能闻出来？
This man… He knew it contained an aphrodisiac
这个人…他早知道里面有春药
and tried to make me eat it?
还要我试吃？
I want to ask you one other thing.
我想问你另外一件事
What is it?
什么事？
The other day,
前几天
there was a foreign combat troop out on an expedition.
有个征讨异族的兵团正在远征
-They were poisoned. -Poisoned?
-他们被下毒了 -下毒？
Many of the soldiers that ate the meal
许多吃过饭菜的士兵
had symptoms of nausea and difficulty breathing. Many got sick.
都出现恶心和呼吸困难的症状 很多人都生病了
Nausea and difficulty breathing?
恶心和呼吸困难？
The meal was prepared at a nearby village.
饭菜是在附近的村庄准备的
The village head was captured for siding with the foreigners,
村长由于支持异族而被关押了
but one soldier controlled the situation, and the punishment remains undecided.
但有位士兵将场面控制住 惩处方式尚待定夺
Normally, one would think
一般而言 大家会认为
that the villagers poisoned the meal, but…
是村民下的毒 但是…
Sir Jinshi, where was this meal eaten?
壬氏大人 他们用餐的地点在哪儿？
They were camping, so outside.
他们在野营 所以是在户外用餐
Were the bowls, chopsticks, and spoons prepared by villagers as well?
碗筷和汤匙也是村民准备的吗？
No, the soldiers prepared it themselves.
不是 是士兵自己带在身上的
Have you realized something?
你想到了什么吗？
This is just an opinion.
这只是我的看法
This flower is called a rhododendron.
这朵花叫做杜鹃花
Is it tasty?
好吃吗？
No. If you eat it, you get nausea and difficulty breathing.
不 如果吃下肚 就会感到恶心和呼吸困难
Hey!
喂！
As you can see, there are many poisonous plants even in the rear palace.
如你所见 就连后宫 都有很多有毒植物
With these, the leaves are poisonous,
以这种植物而言 有毒的部位是叶子
but some have poison in the branches and roots.
但有些植物有毒的部位在枝条和根部
Some plants become poisonous from burning the raw wood.
有些植物在原木燃烧的时候 会产生毒素
Just by burning it?
光是燃烧便有毒素？
I see…
原来如此…
It was good that a rational soldier was present.
好险现场有位理性的士兵
He prevented one village from being burned down.
他阻止了一个村庄被烧毁
Yes…
对…
-If we're finished here, I'm off. -No, wait.
-若没我的事 我先告退了 -不行 等一下
Is there anything else?
还有什么吩咐吗？
Will you make a stimulant potion?
可以请你做春药吗？
Make a potion? In other words…
做春药？也就是说…
Medicine preparation?
准备药物？
With time, the ingredients, and the tools,
有时间、药材和工具的话
I can make something with that effect.
我可以做出有那种效用的东西
Sir Jinshi. Where are you off to?
壬氏大人 您要去哪儿？
I'm returning to my office.
我要回我的房间
Can I help you?
有什么事吗？
It's nothing… Would you like some tea in my room?
没事…你想来我房间喝杯茶吗？
Unfortunately, I have work left to do. Excuse me.
太可惜了 我还有工作 我先告辞了
I wonder if the palace women really haven't realized
不晓得宫女是否真的没发现
that you are an investigator who measures their loyalty
你是替皇上评估她们忠诚度的
to the Emperor.
调查员
Inviting other men to bed because the Emperor will not visit them…
因为得不到皇上的临幸 而找其他男人同寝
-How imprudent. -Truly.
-太不谨慎了 -没错
A concubine cannot just be beautiful and well-educated.
妃子只有美丽和受过教育是不够的
They need to be loyal to the Emperor and be chaste.
她们还需要对皇上忠诚和保持贞操
Placing you in the rear palace
派你去后宫
to use your beauty as a test for the concubines' loyalty…
是要利用你俊美的外表 来测试众嫔妃的忠诚度
The Lord can be cruel.
皇上还真是苛刻
He uses what he can.
他会无所不用其极
However… Not only was she not tempted by me, but she saw me
然而…她不仅没有受到我的诱惑
with those eyes…
竟然还用那种眼神看我…
It's the first time I was regarded with such contempt!
这还是我生平第一次被鄙视
I'll be off then.
我先下去了
You may get a visit tonight…
今晚可能会有人去探视你…
A visit… A visit…
探视…
I'll be off then.
我出门咯
-Yes. Good luck. -Yes, ma'am!
-好 加油 -好的
Excuse me.
不好意思
The quack doctor, and…
那个庸医…
Hello. Let me introduce myself.
猫猫大人 初次见面
My name is Gaoshun.
我叫高顺
I usually work as an aide to Sir Jinshi.
我通常会在壬氏大人身边辅佐他
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Hello.
你好
It must be hard to be an aide to "that"…
辅佐“那个人”想必很辛苦吧…
She's just an attendant… Why…?
她只是一名侍女 为什么…
Intruding in my territory…
侵犯我的领域…
Right this way.
这边请
You're free to use whatever you'd like in here.
这儿的东西你尽管用
Is that some kind of cursed dance?
那是某种诅咒之舞吗？
What a luxury to be able to use this much paper.
能够使用这种等级的纸张 也太奢侈了吧
All right, next up…
好的 下一个…
This, right?
这个 是吗？
He's very observant.
他的观察力非常好
Compared to him, his master…
跟他比起来 他的主人就…
If you're not doing anything, go away!
如果你只是站在那儿无所事事 就走开啦
Here you are.
好了
Thank you.
谢谢
It's not enough…
还不够…
-What is this? -This is cocoa.
-这是什么？ -是可可
If this isn't enough, just get more.
如果不够的话 再拿多一点便是
These are obtained from the southern lands of the Far West.
但这来自于西域以西的南方岛屿
We should be able to find it among the trade items.
我们应该能够在贸易商品当中找到
Milk, butter,
牛奶、黄油
sugar, honey, and powdered cocoa.
糖、蜂蜜和可可粉
All this should be enough.
这些应该就够了
It's all expensive items.
全都是昂贵的食材
I wonder what she's making?
不晓得她在做什么？
Maybe a snack!
也许是点心
What are you three doing?
你们三个在干嘛？
-Get back to work! -We're sorry!
-快回去工作 -对不起
Geez!
真是的
Now, time to prepare the stimulant potion!
现在该做春药了
I've eaten cocoa once before.
我曾吃过一次可可
This is called chocolate, Maomao.
这叫做巧克力 猫猫
Maomao?
猫猫？
An evil customer gifted it to win the affection
那是一个有邪念的客人 为了赢得一名
of a popular courtesan,
受欢迎的妓女芳心而送的礼物
but unfortunately, he was banned from ever entering by Grams.
但不幸的是 老鸨禁止他再踏进青楼一步
All set.
好了
I'll chill these, and…
先把这些放凉…
Now, I have to wait for it to harden.
现在得等它变硬
There's some left over.
还剩下一些原料
I know!
我知道了
No need to chill these.
没有必要冷却这些
Now, I'll do the dishes.
现在来洗碗吧
Are those medicinal herbs?
那些是草药吗？
Here! And here, too! And here!
这儿有 这儿也有 那儿还有
I lost track of time.
不知不觉时间就过去了
I'm sorry for being late!
很抱歉来晚了
Huh?
什么？
What?
怎么了？
At least, now I know it works.
至少我现在知道那的确有用
What's going on?
这究竟是怎么回事？
There's nothing to explain…
我无话可说…
It's all right. They haven't done anything…
不要紧啦 她们什么都没做…
So this is the stimulant we discussed?
这就是我们说的春药？
No. These are for you.
不是 这些才是要给您的
So what is this?
那这些是什么？
These are my snacks.
这些是我的消夜
If you're used to alcohol and stimulants,
如果习惯了酒精和刺激性的食物
the effects are not strong.
效果就不会那么强烈
I see, in that case, there should be no trouble if I eat these.
这样的话 如果我吃的话 应该就不会惹出什么麻烦
-Please don't!
-请不要做这种事
I'm kidding.
我开玩笑的
What an inappropriate statement in front of the Emperor's favorite.
在皇上的宠妃面前 说这些话真是不恰当
But if that face came to tempt you with flushed cheeks…
但如果那张脸 带着泛红晕的双颊来诱惑人的话…
I'm sure that most men and women couldn't resist.
肯定大部分的男女都抵抗不了
He's pointlessly beautiful.
他美得没有天理
The effects are strong, so please have only one at a time.
效果很强 所以一次食用一颗就好
Too much will circulate your blood
吃太多的话 会血液循环过快
and give you a nosebleed.
让你流鼻血
Maybe I'll request some for the Emperor one day.
我下次给皇上拿一些好了
I have to keep it spicy.
我得维持我们之间的火花
It should be three times more powerful than regular tonics…
它的威力应该是普通补品的三倍
Three times?
三倍？
You mean, he'd last three times as long?
你的意思是说 他会有三倍的持久度？
I'll pretend I didn't hear.
我会假装我没听到
Also, please only use this
还有 请在你和心仪的对象
when you're alone with your love interest.
单独相处时再拿出来使用
I see.
了解
All right. I'll be taking my leave now.
好的 我先离开了
She can make medicine, huh?
她会制药呢
She's very reliable.
真是非常可靠
I'm finally finished…
我终于完成了…
You worked hard.
你辛苦了
Thank you.
谢谢
I see.
原来是这样
I hope there won't be any victims…
希望不会有受害者…
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Next episode, "The Unsettling Matter of the Spirit."
下一集 《幽灵作祟》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：欧德慧